

# Ray Berry

# **SUMMARY - iOS Developer**

I am a highly experienced IT professional with a background in financial, retail and automotive industries. I'm an iOS developer with two years experience in Swift and Xcode. I have developed and published my own Apps on the App Store and I am also a qualified Scrum Master. Please review my App portfolio in the link just below.



rayberryrb@gmail.com



07951 010595



# App Portfolio



Bourne, Nr Peterborough

in linkedin.com/in/rav-berry

# **KEY SKILLS**

- iOS Developer
  Swift
  Xcode
  Github
  Firebase
  CoreData
  Realm
  CoreML
  ARKit
- Rest API
  JSON
  Cocoapods
  Carthage
  Alamofire
  MVC
  Tableviews
  Collection Views
  SpriteKit
- VideoStreaming(HLS)
  User Authentication (FaceID, TouchID)
- Agile Scrum Master-PSM1 Project Management Jira Confluence Sprint planning
- UI/UX Design
  Wireframes
  Mock-ups
  Human Interface Guidelines
- TDD XCTest XCUITest
- ERP process integration
  B2B
  EDI
  XML
  AS2

# EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

iOS Developer 10/2017 - Present Bourne, UK

- Good knowledge of Swift and Xcode.
- Developed the following Apps:
  - ScrumIT Scrum Planning Poker using Fibonacci numbers and collection views.
  - FileIT Inventory Management to track inventory to assist with home insurance or moving house. Uses Core Data, User Authentication and Core Graphics animation.
  - Weather using Rest APIs, JSON and GPS location data to retrieve weather data.
  - To do list using Realm and Core Data to store shopping/to do list persistent data.
  - Chat using Firebase Cloud Services to register users and store chat data.
  - Flower classification using CoreML and the Caffe model to take photos of flowers to confirm the type of flower that is in the photo. Experience of CreateML to develop my own
  - Augmented Reality Tape measure using ARkit and Scenekit to measure 3D objects.
  - Video Streaming using HLS (Http Live Streaming) to showcase apps that I have developed.
- Agile qualified Scrum Master PSM1 certification.
- UI/UX Design experience of creating wireframes and mock-ups.

## **Development Manager**

**BGL Group Ltd** 

2012 - 10/2017

Peterborough UK

- Successfully managed an IT development team of between four and eight people delivering internal financial insurance software development projects.
- Scrum Master for a development team. Knowledge and use of Scrum Agile processes including: sprint planning; daily stand-ups; two week sprint cycles; sprint reviews and retrospectives.
- Understanding and using the Atlassian tools: Jira and Confluence to manage sprints and update product backlog.

## **NEU IS Supply Services Lead**

Reckitt Benckiser

2010 - 2012

Hull, UK

- Managing a cross-section of IT projects ranging from senior management reporting, cost reduction exercises, automation of business interfaces between JDE and Siebel; Manugistics and EDI packages.
- The project management encompassed resource allocation, budget control, prioritisation, risk analysis, project delivery and post implementation reviews.

#### **European IS Supply Services Lead**

Reckitt Benckiser

2006 - 2009

Hull, UK

Project managing teams as well as working with external off-shore support from Bangalore, India to ensure implementation of a demand planning tool (Manugistics 7.2) across sixteen countries in Europe. Managing project budget for Europe for over £1m for Manugistics rollouts.

## **EDI Senior Business Analyst**

Reckitt Benckiser

2003 - 2006

- I was responsible for EDI within Europe for RB. I was responsible for a team of five supporting the EDI infrastructure within seventeen countries across Europe.
- Consultancy role on EDI interface design and development into JD Edwards.
- Good EDI mapping experience using Inovis TLI series visual mapper. Mapping in TRADACOM, EDIFACT, ANSI X12 and EANCOM subsets i.e HANCOM. Written code in RPG for interface routines.

#### **Freelance EDI Consultant**

Freelance

1998 - 2003

Chiswick/Slough, UK

EDI integration specialist in BPCS and JD Edwards using Harbinger /Inovis Trusted Link I series EDI interfacing products and RPG.

## **EDUCATION**

# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Cambridge College of Arts and Technology

Swift RPG

HND in Software Engineering

COBOL

Knowsley Tertiary College

BASIC

OND in Computer Studies

Higherside Comprehensive School

7 O' levels including Maths, English and Computer Studies

GitHub Repository

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

2014 - Round Table President (Bourne)

2014 - Burghley Rat Race 20 Mile Assault course

2008 - Round Table Chairman (Bourne)

2006 - London Marathon

2005 - BUPA North Half Marathon